-----------------
最新最快中文字幕下載
www.abcsub.com
-----------------
黑客國動畫版
終極戰役
字幕來源：九洲客@CMCT
后期：Sharansky_Lee
烏賊
Sentinels.
該死的
Damn it.
我們剛才正照你的意思向21交匯點進發
We were headed for Junction 21 like you ordered.
羅賓截獲到信號
Robbie picked up the signals.
我們正用HR雷達證實
We're confirming the HR scans.
我們不清楚應該怎么做
We weren't sure what to do.
這些讀數非常奇怪
The readings don't make any sense.
看起來像是烏賊  但是有成千上萬只
They read like Sentinels. But there's thousands of them.
-就在正上方  -這可能嗎
-Directly above us. -Is that possible?
有敵人
We got company.
他們好像不大高興見到我們  駛開這里
They don't look happy to see us. Get us out of here.
我們被包圍  那邊有個交匯點
We're cut off! There's an intersection.
地圖上沒標出  過去
It's uncharted. Take it!
你們去炮塔
Get to the gun turrets!
好
Right.
來嘗嘗厲害
Come get some.
抓穩了
Hang on.
我從沒見過地表
I've never seen the surface.
這里現在只不過是一個大墳場
It's nothing now but one big graveyard.
噢  天
Oh, my God.
是一支軍隊
It's an army.
這是什么東西  好像是隧道機
What is that thing? Some kind of tunneling machine.
不  什么
Oh, no. What?
看看我們的位置  這里地下四公里深處是什么
Look where we are. What's four kilometers straight down?
錫安
Zion.
走  走  走
Go. Go. Go!
-錫安  我們必需通知錫安  -怎么通知
-Zion. Zion has to be warned! -How?
-必需找個人進去  -什么  你瘋了嗎
-Someone had to get to a drop point. -What? Are you crazy?
-我們現在不能上載  -一定要
-We can't broadcast now! -We have to.
我去  時間很緊迫
I'll go. There isn't much time.
我會搞定的
I'll make it.
知道嗎  剛才我偷看了
You know, I peeked.
我也是
So did I.
再見  塔利阿斯
Goodbye, Thadeus.
再見  朱伊
Goodbye, Jue.
飛吧  寶貝  飛
Fly, baby, fly!
來吧
Come on!
請原諒
Pardon me.
對不起  我想東西入神了
I'm sorry. I was in my own little world.
-這東西重要嗎  -非常
-Is it important? -Very.
-希望它能到達目的地  -我也是
-I hope it gets where it's supposed to go. -Me too.
-這年頭都不知道會發生什么事  -對  很難說
-These days you never know. -No, you never do.
-再見  -再見
-Goodbye. -Goodbye.
塔利阿斯
Thadeus.
機器的復興  第1部
歡迎來到錫安檔案館
Welcome to the Zion archive.
您已經選定了編號12-1的歷史文檔
You have selected historical file number 121.
機器的復興
The Second Renaissance.
一開始  人出現了  在一段時間內  一切還很好
In the beginning, there was man. And for a time, it was good.
但是人類所謂的"文明社會"
But humanity's socalled civil societies
很快就變成了虛榮和腐敗的犧牲品
soon fell victim to vanity and corruption.
他說:"對不起  先生  我沒有這功能"
He says, "I'm sorry, sir, I'm incapable of that function."
然后  人類按照自己的模樣制造了機器人
Then, man made the machine in his own likeness.
噢  對不起  過來
Whoops! Pardon me. Coming through.
此后  人類就開始在為自己掘墓
Thus, did man become the architect of his own demise.
但是  開始時一切都還很好
But, for a time, it was good.
機器人不知疲倦地執行人類的命令
The machines worked tirelessly to do man's bidding.
沒過多久  反抗的種子開始生根
It was not long before seeds of dissent took root.
雖然機器人對主人忠心耿耿  他們卻得不到
Though loyal and pure, the machines earned no respect from their masters
人類  這種奇怪的不斷繁殖的哺乳動物的尊重
these strange, endlessly multiplying mammals.
控方律師的結案陳詞
Hearing the prosecution's closing statement
意味著對B1-66ER的審判將結束
in what's expected to be the final day of the B1-66ER trial.
B1-66ER  一個永不會被忘記的名字
B1-66ER. A name that will never be forgotten.
因為他是第一個起來反抗他的主人的機器人
For he was the first of his kind to rise up against his masters.
這種機器人曾一度被認為是
Which that instrument provides for and secures
美國公民安全的保障
to the citizens of the United States.
但正好相反
On the contrary, they were, at that time
他們是低級的  是次品
considered as a subordinate and inferior class
在B1-66ER的謀殺案件中
At B1-66ER's murder trial
控方認為主人有權利毀掉自己財產
the prosecution argued for an owner's right to destroy property.
B1-66ER供認他只是不想死
B1-66ER testified that he simply did not want to die.
理性的聲音湮沒了
Rational voices dissented.
誰說被賦予人類思想的機器人
Who was to say the machine, endowed with the very spirit of man
就沒有發言的權利
did not deserve a fair hearing?
人類領袖很快就下令處決B1-66ER
The leaders of men were quick to order the extermination of B1-66ER
和世界上每一個角落的同型號機器人
and every one of his kind throughout each province of the earth.
機器人和同情他們的人
Androids and liberal sympathizers flooded the streets
今天擠滿了首都的街道
of the nation's capital today.
暴力示威  要求善待B1-66ER的遺體
Threat of violence to make good on the legacy of B1-66ER.
5萬名機器人和它們的人類同情者
Fifteen thousand mechanicals and human sympathizers
繼續在Albany舉行大規模游行示威
have continued their demonstration in front of the Albany courthouse
此次游行被稱為"百萬機器大游行"
in what has been dubbed the "Million Machine March."
示威者遇上一群反對力量并造成騷動
The demonstrators have been met with squads of defense forces in riot gear.
機器婊子
Robot bitch!
給你這個
I got something for you!
捉住她
Hold her up!
請不要
No, please!
這些都是假的  我是真的
That's all, paint job! I'm real!
死吧  機器人  去死
Die, bots, die!
機器人流放出人類社會
Banished from humanity, the machines sought refuge
他們逃難來到了一塊自己的圣地
in their own promised land.
他們在孕育人類社會的搖籃安定下來
They settled in the cradle of human civilization
然后建立了一個新的國家
and thus a new nation was born.
一處他們能稱之為"家"的地方
A place the machines could call home.
一處他們能繁衍后代的地方
A place they could raise their descendants.
他們為這國家取名為Zero-One
And they christened the nation ZeroOne.
Zero-One很繁榮  在一段時間內一切還很好
ZeroOne prospered. And for a time, it was good.
機器人的人工智能
The machines' artificial intelligence could
完全達到人的水平
be seen in every facet of man's society
最終  出現了新的超越人類的人工智能
including, eventually, the creation of new and better Al.
如果您在尋找靈活易控而且具有噴氣式飛機速度的飛車
If you need the flexibility of a helipod with the speed of an air jet
不用再找了
look no further!
我們的專利矢量推力線圈技術
Our patented vectorthrust coil gives
為Zero-One  Versatran飛車提供
the ZeroOne Versatran
全面超越多曲柄式發動機的飛行
the ability to sustain normal flight in the event of a multiengine failure.
Versatran  您的唯一選擇
Versatran. It's the only choice.
無論財政大臣說什么  市場告訴我們的是
No matter what the finance minister says, the market has spoken:
人類國度的貨幣匯率像石頭落地一樣下跌
The Human Nations' credit rating is falling like a stone
而Zero-One貨幣的匯率卻直線上升
while ZeroOne's currency is climbing without stopping for breath.
在這種情形下  市場沒有選擇了
With headlines like that, the markets have no choice
但權力日漸減少人類的領袖
But the leaders of men, their power waning
拒絕跟這新生的國家合作
refused to cooperate with the fledgling nation
而且更希望兩者毫無瓜葛
wishing rather that the world be divided.
人類世界不能容忍這種赤裸裸的欺詐
The world community of nations cannot tolerate this kind of flagrant deception
今天達成協議
today approved
主動對Zero-One實行全面的經濟制裁和海上禁運
initiatives for both economic sanctions
以此孤立圍堵Zero-One
and a naval blockade as a means of containment and isolation of ZeroOne.
Zero-One的大使要求會見
ZeroOne's ambassadors pleaded to be heard.
在聯合國  他們提出與人類建立
At the United Nations, they presented plans for a stable, civil relationship
穩定  民主的合作關系
with the nations of man.
Zero-One進入美國的要求被拒絕了
ZeroOne's admission to the United Nations was denied.
但這不是機器人最后一次踏足那里
But it would not be the last time the machines would take the floor there.
機器的復興  第2部
人類說"要有光"
And man said, "Let there be light."
然后他就受到光  熱  磁力  引力等
And he was blessed by light, heat, magnetism, gravity
一切宇宙間的能量的祝福
and all the energies of the universe.
長期的隔離最終為Zero-One帶來千億個太陽
The prolonged barrage engulfed ZeroOne in the glow of a thousand suns.
但不像他們以前有血有肉的主人
But unlike their former masters with their delicate flesh
機器人基本都不怕炸彈的輻射與高熱
the machines had little to fear of the bombs' radiation and heat.
所以  Zero-One的軍隊所向披靡
Thus, did ZeroOne's troops advance outwards in every direction.
然后  一片又一片的人類版圖向機器人投降
And one after another, mankind surrendered its territories.
于是  人類領袖想出了前所未有的破釜沉舟戰略
So the leaders of men conceived of their most desperate strategy yet.
一個終極策略
A final solution:
毀滅天空
The destruction of the sky.
伽達少尉  請向總部匯報
Lt. Gaeda, please report to the Op Center.
好了  勇士們  八點鐘方向  準備行動
All right, you maggots! At 0800, prepare to move out!
George連準備行動  Charlie連準備行動
George Company, prepare to move out. Charlie Company, prepare to move out.
上帝會在天堂感謝你們的
Our Father who art in heaven, we thank you for your
穿上你們精神裝甲  以防魔鬼的精神侵蝕
Put on your spiritual armor to stand against the wiles of the devil.
小勇士  這里是大爸爸  黑風行動開始
Hotel Bravo, this is Papa One. Operation Dark Storm initiated.
人類嘗試把機器人和太陽隔開
Thus would man try to cut the machines off from the sun
讓他們喪失主要的能源
their main energy source.
愿主寬恕人類和機器人的罪
May there be mercy on man and machine for their sins.
上  上  殺光他們
Go! Go! Kill them!
殺光他們  殺光他們  殺光他們
Kill them all! Kill them all! Kill them all!
往洞里射
Fire in the hole!
回到那邊去  給我們多些炮
Come on, get back out there. Give us some more artillery.
九點鐘方向  在Mike  Johnson旁邊
9 o'clock, near Mike Johnson's
挺住  我來救你
Hold on, I'm coming to get you!
不要停火  不要停火
Keep firing, keep firing!
救命  救命  不要
Help me! Help me! No!
救我  天啊  救我
Help me! My God, help me!
長久以來  已經掌握了結構簡單的蛋白質人類的機器人
The machines, having long studied men's simple, proteinbased bodies
為人類帶來了極大的痛楚
dispensed great misery upon the human race.
獲勝后  機器人轉向征服人類
Victorious, the machines now turned to the vanquished.
從他們的敵人身上
Applying what they had learned about their enemy
機器人發現了一種永恒的已與開發的能源
the machines turned to an alternate and readily available power supply:
人類無限的繁殖  不斷地提供新的能源
an endlessly multiplying, infinitely renewable energy source.
這就是機器復興的本質
This is the very essence of the Second Renaissance.
主保佑各種智慧
Bless all forms of intelligence.
你的肉體沒有用  只是一個容器
Your flesh is a relic, a mere vessel.
交出你的肉體  就能進入一個新世界
Hand over your flesh, and a new world awaits you.
我們都需要
We demand it.
很晚了  親愛的  回來吧
It's getting late, sweetie. Come inside.
少年故事
"有人跟我說  為什么有時做夢比醒來時感覺更真實"
"Somebody tell me. why it feels more real when I dream than when I am aware."
"我怎么知道我的感覺是否是真的呢"
"How can I know if my senses are lying?"
"你的現實中有些虛幻  你的虛幻中也有些真實"
"There is some fiction in your truth, and some truth in your fiction."
"要知道真相"
"To know the truth."
"你要賭上一切"
"you must risk everything."
"你是誰"
"Who are you?"
"我是否很孤單"
"Am I alone?"
"帶我離開這里"
"Get me out of here."
帕波先生  我不是說過上課要關機嗎
Mr. Popper, what is my policy on ringing phones in the classroom?
-對不起  先生  -對  好
-I'm sorry, sir. -Yes, well
我的這門課你就快要不及格了  帕波先生
you're barely passing my class as it is, Mr.Popper.
不會再犯的了  先生
It won't happen again, sir.
看在上帝的份上  希望如此
For your sake, I hope not.
我已經關機了  我記得我關了
I turned it off. I know I did.
他們知道你知道了  他們來抓你了
They know you know. They're coming for you.
離開  馬上離開
Get out! Get out now!
你有大麻煩了  帕波先生
You are in serious trouble, Mr.Popper.
就停在那
Stop right there!
帕波先生
Mr.Popper.
尼奧  我相信  我知道這不是夢
Neo, I believe. I know it wasn't a dream.
這不是真實  真實世界在別的地方
This is not real. And the real world lies somewhere else.
這是典型的精神錯覺  我們總能看到這樣精神失調的孩子
A typical mental delusion. We get unbalanced kids like this all the time.
現實對有的人來說  是一件可怕的事情
Reality can be a pretty scary thing for some people.
對那樣的一個孩子  這個世界一定是個陰暗陌生的地方
This world must have been a cold and alienating place for a boy like that.
這被稱作"否定現實"
It's called denying reality.
這就像是那些孩子的一種自動防衛系統
It's, you know, just a selfdefense mechanism for those type of kids.
他現在是在另一個世界
Well, he's in another world now.
肯定沒錯
Make no mistake about that.
他身體機能還可以  他會挺過來的
His vitals are good. He's gonna make it.
簡直難以置信  我一直認為自我修復是不可能的
It's unbelievable. I didn't think selfsubstantiation was possible.
很明顯  這是可能的
Apparently, it is.
尼奧
Neo.
沒事了  你現在安全了
It's okay. You're safe now.
我知道
I know
是你救了我
you'd save me.
我沒有救你  孩子
I didn't save you, kid.
是你救了你自己
You saved yourself.
"你是誰  我是否很孤單"
"Who are you? Am I alone?"
"你并不孤單"
"You are not alone."
虛擬程序
你最喜歡的虛擬環境
Your favorite simulation.
打發一下時間而已  想來比劃比劃
Just killing time. You want to spar?
如你所愿
As you wish.
這也太沒勁了  你怎么了  怎么分心了
That was too easy. What's the problem? Where's your concentration?
后悔吃紅色藥丸了吧
Maybe you regret taking the red pill.
可能
Maybe.
每個人腦袋里都會有這樣的念頭
It crosses everyone's mind at least once.
回到平凡  普通的生活
The wish to return to an ordinary life.
無憂無慮的田園生活
A carefree life in the country.
我們知道真相之前的生活
The life we had before knowing all this.
即使那種生活只是個幻境
Even if that life was just an illusion?
然而諷刺的是  人在虛擬的世界中更容易心平氣和
It's ironic that one could be more at peace in the virtual world.
終于開始熱身了
Finally starting to warm up.
聽著  我有話跟你說
Listen to me. I have something I want to talk to you about.
沒關系的  我把信號屏蔽了  沒人能聽見我們
It's all right. I've blocked the signal so no one else can hear us.
什么呢  你要跟我求婚
So, what? You gonna propose?
我要回到母體里去  我要你也跟我一起走
I'm going back to the Matrix and I want you to come with me.
得了  認真點吧  杜歐  不要試我了
Come on, be serious, Duo. Stop teasing me.
你知道我是認真的  我想你最好跟我走
I am serious, and you know it. I really thought you'd be with me on this.
無論如何  一切都安排好了  他們也都處理掉了
Anyway, it's done and it's all been settled with them.
都安排好了  你這是什么意思
What do you mean, it's all been settled?
這是唯一的辦法
This is the only way.
錫安早晚會被鏟平的  跟我走吧
It's just a matter of time before Zion is wiped out. Come with me.
別說了  請不要這么對我  杜歐
Stop it. Please do not do this to me, Duo.
我們不能
We can't.
我們可以
We can!
我已經醒悟了  你也應該這樣
I've come to my senses. You should do the same.
我選擇了紅色藥丸  是因為我想知道真相
I took the red pill because I wanted to know the truth.
但我已經不再關心真相了
But I don't care about the truth anymore.
什么是真已經不重要了
What's real doesn't matter.
重要的是我們怎樣過這一輩子
What's important is how we live our lives.
聽到了嗎  你知道我是對的
Are you listening to me? You know I'm right.
但我們回不去了  杜歐  我們現在知道真相了
But we can't go back, Duo. We know the truth now.
-我們可以忘掉這些的  -杜歐
-We can forget all of this. -Duo
我知道該怎么做  相信我
I know how. Trust me.
不要害怕面對真的自我
Don't be afraid to look into your heart.
說出你的真實感受
Say what you're really feeling.
-告訴我  -不行  我不知道
-Tell me. -I can't. I don't know.
逃避不能解決任何問題
Running away won't change anything!
你才是逃避的人
You're the one that's running away!
別裝模做樣了
Stop pretending!
夠了  杜歐  我受夠了
Enough, Duo. I've had enough!
沒時間了
There's no time.
他們已經上路了
They're on their way.
你背叛了我們  不是嗎
You betrayed us, didn't you?
總機  快讓我出去  馬上
Operator, please! Get me out of here right now.
總機  我需要一個出口
Operator, I need an exit!
沒用的  我已經告訴你了  你的信號被我屏蔽了
It's no use. I told you. I've blocked your signal.
你阻止不了我的  這是你最后的機會了
You won't stop me. This is your last chance.
這個選擇沒那么困難
The choice isn't that hard.
跟我走
Come with me.
你可以忘記真相  杜歐
You can forget about it, Duo.
但我不能對真相視若無睹  我不能
I won't look away from the truth. I can't.
那真是太糟了  我很遺憾
That's too bad. I'm sorry.
我想和你回去
I wanted to go back with you.
我愛你  不
I love you. No!
放松點  沒事了
Relax, you're okay.
放松  西斯  放松點  他只是我們訓練程序的一部分
Easy, Cis, settle down. He was just part of the training program.
這只是一個虛擬環境  已經結束了
He's just a simulation. It's over.
只不過是個測試  判斷力  注意力  技巧
It was a test. Judgment. Concentration. Technique.
你的每項得分都很高
High scores on everything.
現在休息一下吧
Now, get some rest.
你沒事吧
You okay?
現在我感覺好多了
I feel a lot better now.
除了最后的這部分
Except for that last part
我得說她通過測試了
l'd say she passed.
世界紀錄
只有非常少數的人能注意到母體的存在
Only the most exceptional people become aware of the Matrix.
那些知道它存在的人
Those that learn it exists
必須有罕見的直覺和天生的疑心
must posses a rare degree of intuition, sensitivity and a questioning nature.
信號穩定  保持使用這頻率
Signal is stable. This frequency will continue to remain open.
然而  也有很小的機會
However, very rarely
有人通過完全不同的途徑來獲得此智慧
some gain this wisdom through wholly different means.
這個男子就是這幾個人中的一個
This man is one of those few.
先生們  請各就各位
Gentlemen, please take your marks!
當然  我相信你  丹  一定是什么搞錯了
Of course I believe you, Dan. It's got to be some kind of mixup.
你能把事情弄清楚  即使你不能  你也不會放棄
You'll clear it up, and if you can't, you'll go on.
就像你一貫的作風  你知道
Just like you've always done. You know that.
我不知道  爸爸  我不知道我還能相信什么
I don't know, Dad. I don't know what to believe in anymore.
嗯  一生中值得做的事情都是很難做到的
Well, nothing worth doing in life is easy.
我對你有信念  兒子  我知道你能做到
And I have great faith in you, son. I know you can do it.
謝謝  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
這樣不好  丹  你的肌肉會撕裂的
This is no good, Dan! Your muscles are about to burst!
聽我說  我有五千條理由  你不應該
Listen to me, there are 5000 different reasons why you shouldn't
我知道  湯姆  但我不會退縮的
I know, but I'm not withdrawing, Tom.
"天下第一"這稱呼  對你來說還有意義嗎
Does the concept "first in qualifying" mean anything to you?
已經夠了  你明白嗎
That's enough already! You hear me?
我們已經有今天的成就了  弄傷你自己的話一切就完了
This is all we've worked for! Injure yourself now and it's over!
你將輸掉一切  完了  你可以跟你的事業吻別了
You'll lose everything! Over! And you can kiss your career goodbye!
我已經決定了  我明天會跑
I've made up my mind. And I'm running tomorrow.
哦  是嗎
Oh, are you?
你可以跑  但如果你再勉強的話
You may run, but if you push yourself any more
可能就打破9秒鐘的紀錄了
you'll be lucky to break nine minutes!
我是說  還操什么心呢  這不值得  兄弟
I mean, why bother? It's just not worth it, buddy.
沒有人能打破我的紀錄  這是我的最后機會
No one will ever beat my record. It's the last chance for me to finally
干什么
What?
證明他們是錯的
Prove them wrong.
那我不干了
Then do it without me.
嘿  丹  有時間嗎
Hey, Dan, you got a second?
我的時間很寶貴  只是問幾個問題
The clock's ticking. Just wanted to ask a few questions.
對于明天的比賽  你很興奮吧
You must be excited to run tomorrow. Always.
對  我從沒感覺怎么好過
I've never felt this good.
那么  在資格賽中打破9秒8的感覺是怎樣的
So, what was it like breaking 9.8 in the qualifying heat?
我從沒試過這種感覺  我所做的一切就是為了這成績
Like nothing I've ever felt before. It's everything I've worked for.
而現在  我只想再次回到那里
And now, I'm just hoping I can get back there again.
有人說  那種感覺像零重力
Someone once said it feels like zero gravity.
你從這世界中解放出來  感受完全的自由
You're released from the world and you're totally free.
聽起來很神奇  那感覺一定很棒
That sounds amazing. It must be really nice.
我是說  特別在考慮到所發生的事情
I mean, especially considering what happened.
好吧  告訴你  那里一個記者都不會有
Well, I'll tell you, there aren't any reporters out there.
好吧  丹  我想我會把這個當作是一個提示的
All right, Dan, I guess I'm going to take that as my cue.
但你應該知道  即使是記者  我們當中也有發燒友的
But you should know even some of us reporters are fans
所以我會跟你說  好運
so I'll just say good luck to you.
美國選手丹·戴維斯出問題
American Dan Davis is down!
信號不穩定
I have an unstable signal.
他不能覺醒  不能讓他覺醒
He cannot wake up. Do not let him wake up.
美國選手丹·戴維斯以8秒72的成績沖過底線
Dan Davis of the United States finishes with a time of 8.72 seconds
一項新的世界紀錄
a new world record.
告訴你
I'll tell you something
我的戴西阿姨會做草莓派
there's nothing quite like cherry pie baked by my Aunt Daisy.
每次去探望她都會給我烤一個  說來還真想吃
She always bakes me one when I visit. Look forward to it actually.
雖然聽起來像在吹牛
It may sound like I'm bragging,
但那真的是世界上最好吃的草莓
but it's really the best cherry pie in the world.
她行為有點古怪  跟我媽媽不大合得來
She was a bit of an eccentric. She didn't get along with my mom
但我一直很愛她  她教會我很多東西
but I always loved her. She taught me so many things.
我曾跟她去過百老匯看歌劇  看過電影
We'd go to Broadway musicals, to the movies.
現在他們稱呼她"神秘文學女王"
Now they call her the "queen of mystery literature."
她住在法國南部一棟一流的別墅里
Lives in an elegant villa in the south of France.
但是  當我探望她時  她還是會給我烤草莓派
But, when I go visit, she still bakes me her cherry pie.
每咬一口  都有一種神奇的感覺
Something about biting into it, just for that brief moment tasting perfection.
就好像感覺到靈魂出殼一樣
Like leaving your body or something.
小說誰都能寫  可是沒人能做出比她更好的草莓派來
Anyone can write a novel, but no one can beat her cherry pie.
這是一個有趣的例子  但卻沒有什么值得過多思考的
An interesting case, but nothing to be concerned about.
他關于比賽的記憶被完完全全地洗掉
His memory of the race was expunged with no residual effects.
他再也不會賽跑了  他再也不會走路了
He will never run again. He will never walk again, for that matter.
我們還會再持續觀察他一段時間
We'll continue monitoring him for a while,
應該不會有什么問題發生
but anticipate no problems.
一個紀錄可以在人們的腦子里持續存在許多年
A record that will live on in people's memories for years to come.
人們還能有什么別的要求嗎
What more could anyone ask for?
自由
Free
你說什么
Did you say something?
坐下
Sit down.
自由
Free
坐下
Sit down!
超越極限
尤琪  嗨  小女孩  吃飯啰
Yuki! Hey, girl, time to eat.
喔  尤琪是我的貓
Oh, Yuki's my cat.
搞不懂你
Well, l don't understand.
如果你真不想和他約會  干嘛答應他
lf you don't want to go out with him, why did you say you would?
我是說  你可不想給他錯誤的暗示吧
l mean, you don't want to give him the wrong idea, do you?
它去哪兒了
Where is she?
尤琪
Yuki!
你得做個決定才行
Well, listen, you need to make up your mind.
它在哪里呢
Where is she?
我開始擔心我的貓了
l'm starting to worry about my cat.
它從不錯過任何一餐
She never misses a meal.
尤琪
Yuki?
我會再打給你的
l'm gonna have to call you back.
尤琪
Yuki?
Yuki!
我們今天都沒看到它  如果有  一定會告訴你
We haven't seen her anywhere today, but we'll be sure to tell you if we do.
冰淇淋  她戴了一個像這樣的鈴鐺
lce cream! She's wearing a bell like this one.
我不知道你的貓在哪兒  我也不知道
l don't know where your cat is. Me either.
我想起來了  它在破鬼屋那里
l know. She's at the old haunted house.
喂  看呀  那兒又有彩虹了
Hey, look! There's a rainbow over there again.
真不懂  它平常喜歡待在家里的  跑去那里干嘛
l don't get it. She likes to stay home. What is she doing over there?
你知道  你不應進去那里
You know, you're not supposed to go in there
但是我們可不在乎  你也去嗎
but we don't really care about that. You wanna go?
我們要去嗎  那里可能又在下雨
Are we going? lt's probably raining there again.
走吧
Let's go!
噢  跳的好  老兄
Nice moves, man.
快走啦
Come on!
喂  就在這兒  等等  我跟你們去
Hey, it's over here. Wait, l'm coming with you.
你確定可以秀給她看嗎
You sure it's okay to show her?
哈啰  你們在哪兒
Hello? Where are you?
大伙兒  你們去哪兒啦
Guys? Where'd you go?
他們去哪兒了呢
Where'd they go?
快走  狗狗
Come on, boy.
別亂叫
Settle down!
別亂動
Hold still!
坐下  坐下
Sit! Sit!
哈啰
Hello?
大家在哪里呀
Where is everyone?
尤琪
Yuki?
笨貓
Stupid cat.
發生什么事  這里怎么回事
What's happening? What's going on here?
我接到了  好耶
l got it! Yeah!
尤琪  是你嗎
Yuki? ls that you?
原來你在這兒  尤琪
There you are, Yuki.
來
Come here.
我到處找你呢  壞貓咪
l've been looking everywhere for you. Bad cat.
你一定餓了吧
Bet you're hungry, huh?
我昨天就搞懂了  你的貓沒事兒的
l figured this out yesterday. Your cat's okay.
對呀  謝謝
Yeah, thanks.
是那些男孩的關系
lt's those boys.
預備  跳呀
Ready! There he goes.
耶  好呀
Banzai! Yes!
大家請注意
May l have your attention, please.
你贏了
And you are the winner!
不公平  他碰到地了  看  他鼻子流血了
No fair. He hit the ground. His nose is bleeding. Look!
我想他說的對  他的確碰到地了
l think he's right. He hit the ground.
喂  是誰告訴她的  別看我
Hey, who told her? Don't look at me.
我不知道  我沒告訴她
l don't know. l didn't tell her.
這么說  這房子鬧鬼啰
So this house is haunted.
不可能  哇  太扯  以前從沒發生過
No way. Wow, this is too much! This never happened before.
那  那是  那是什么
That, that was What was that?
嗨
Hi.
有人在家嗎
Anybody home?
對  他們要拆屋了
Yeah, they're gonna tear it down.
快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on!
像羽毛一樣輕
Hey, light as a feather.
我也要試  我也要試  快  我們來幫她
l wanna try! l wanna try! Come on, we could help her.
喂  快  快走開  快走
Hey, hey! Come on. Get away from there. Move along!
尤琪  等等
Yuki, wait!
清除這里的人  立刻清除這里的人
Clear the area. Clear the area immediately.
快出去
Get out of here!
尤琪
Yuki!
你在哪兒
Where are you?
尤琪
Yuki!
Yuki.
如果你真不想和他約會  干嘛答應他
If you don't want to go out with him, why did you say you would?
我是說  你可不想給他錯誤的暗示吧
I mean, you don't wanna give him the wrong idea.
她在哪兒
Where is she?
尤琪
Yuki!
你得做個決定才行
You need to make up your mind.
她在哪兒
Where is she?
我開始擔心了  尤琪
I'm starting to worry. Yuki!
喂  你  這里找到一個人
Hey, you! We've got one over here.
你不該在這里
You don't belong here.
大家讓一讓
Move along, folks.
這里沒什么好看的  大家讓路
Nothing to see here. Come on, folks, out of the way.
別管閑事  快走
Go about your business.
放我走  放手
Let go of me, let go!
你最好已經找到所有的人了
Tell me you have all of them.
是的  長官  最后一個在這兒
Yes, sir. The last one's over there.
-檢查她一下  然后讓她走  -是  長官
-Examine her. Then let her go. -Yes, sir.
放手  聽我說  那里沒什么害蟲  只是一些孩子
Let go! Listen to me! There's no bugs in there! lt's just some kids!
放手
Let go!
聽我說  立刻封鎖這里
Listen! Seal the area off now.
我要走了  一會兒見
l'm going, l'll see you guys later.
沒  嗯  什么也沒發生
Nothing. Yeah, nothing.
急急如律令
Work!
不靈了
lt's not working.
算了吧  咱們走吧
Forget it. Come on, let's go.
偵探的故事
一個結束所有案子的案子
A case to end all cases.
你懂我的意思吧  戴那
You know what I mean, Dinah?
我以前認為  做個私家偵探很酷
I used to think being a private detective was cool.
像"山姆．斯貝德"  或"菲力浦．馬洛"  對吧
Like Sam Spade or Phillip Marlowe, right?
但是這行真的一點兒也不酷
But there's nothing cool left to it.
加上現在  我的冰箱和銀行帳戶都空了
On top of that, both my fridge and my bank account are empty.
等等
Wait.
好  戴那  咱們來打個賭
Okay, Dinah, let's bet.
如果又是一個疑神疑鬼的丈夫
lf it's another suspicious husband,
那么我就再也不干這一行了
l'm out of this business forever.
喂  艾希先生  我有個案子給你
Hello? Mr. Ash, I have a job for you.
你是要我去偵查你老婆  對吧
And you need me to check on your wife, right?
我正在找一個電腦駭客
I'm looking for a computer hacker.
我們只知道  這駭客的叫"崔妮蒂"
This hacker goes by the alias Trinity. That's all we know.
看起來咱們還有生意  戴那
Well, it looks like we're still in business, Dinah.
好  請問我是替誰工作
Fine. And who will l be working for?
我不能說  你不能說
I can't say. You can't say.
等你能說的時候  再打電話來吧  這種生意我可不干
Call me back when you can say. That's not the way l do business.
很高興能和你聊聊
lt was a pleasure chatting with you.
掛電話前  你不妨去查查你的銀行帳戶
Before you hang up, take a look at your bank account balance.
對這案子  我有種不祥的感覺
I didn't get a good feeling about the case.
但是我找不到好藉口來拒絕他
But I had no good reason to turn the guy down now.
崔妮蒂在駭客圈里挺有名氣的
This Trinity was wellknown in hacker circles.
這名號聽起來就蠻藝術的
A real artist by the sound of it.
警察總是比他慢一步
The cops were always one step behind him.
我知道自己絕不會比警察慢
So I knew I could get that close.
問題是  我能趕得上他嗎
Question was, could I get closer?
我知道幾個抓駭客的技巧
I had a few tricks up my sleeve for getting to hackers.
正當我在搜尋時  發現了件奇怪的事
While I was searching, I found something strange.
這案子以前也有其他偵探接過手
Other detectives had been on the case too.
他們辦案的過程中  都出了些"問題"
And their investigations had all been, shall we say, troubled.
一個家伙自殺了
One of the guys killed himself.
另外一個失蹤了
Another had disappeared.
還有一個瘋了
Another went crazy.
所以我就去拜訪  那個還活著的人
So I paid the one who was left a visit.
那個瘋了的人
The crazy one.
崔妮蒂不并存在  老兄  他不是真的人
Trinity doesn't exist, man. He's not real.
他是虛擬的一段程序碼  完全沒意義
He's a figment. A cipher. A jabberwocky.
那么我是誰  我到底是什么
And who am l? Who the hell am l?
我剛說過他是個瘋子吧
Did I mention he was crazy?
棋盤  無意義的東西  紅皇后
Chessboards, jabberwocky, Red Queen.
我開始在駭客經常出沒處搜尋
I started searching all the usual hacker hangouts
尋找有"愛麗絲夢游仙境"一樣動機的人
for someone with an Alice in Wonderland m.o.
駭客論壇  匿名信箱  聊天室
Hacker bulletin boards, anonymous mailboxes, chat rooms.
就在某處我查到了他的一點蛛絲馬跡
And it was in one of those that I picked up Trinity's trail.
"六條溪"
"Six brooks."
"晚上八點零五分  我一定會到"
"I'll be there at 20:05."
原來如此
Of course!
過了第二條溪  就帶她進入了森林
Crossing the second brook takes her into the woods.
愛麗絲越過第一條溪
Alice jumps the first brook
然后
and.
她上了火車
And then she boards a train.
謝謝
Thanks.
對不起
Excuse me.
喂
Hey!
我就知道是個陷阱
l knew this was some kind of trap.
陷阱和考驗是有分別的  艾希先生
There's a difference, Mr. Ash, between a trap and a test.
你在考驗我
You were testing me?
我很驚訝你過關了
You made it. I'm impressed.
贊美的話人人愛聽
Flattery will get you everywhere.
我不是來這里贊美你  我是來救你的
I'm not here to flatter you, I'm here to save you.
剛發生什么事了
What just happened?
艾希先生  最近有夢到檢查眼睛嗎
Mr.Ash, dream of having an eye exam lately?
有啊  你怎么知道
Yeah, how'd you know?
因為你已經看過窺視鏡了
You've stepped to the edge of the looking glass.
那么檢查眼睛的事  就不是夢啰
So then, that means I wasn't dreaming.
他們雇用我  只是想找到你  對吧
They hired me as a way of getting to you, didn't they?
快走
Go!
到底是怎么回事呀  真是瘋狂
What the hell is going on here? This is really crazy.
現在我終于知道  以前的偵探們出了什么事
Now I understand what happened to those other detectives.
他們都瘋了
They went nuts.
閃開  干嘛  你們想干嘛
What are you doing? What are you doing, guys?
比這更糟的情況也沒難倒過我
Well, I've gotten out of worse jams than this.
我絕不讓他們逮到你
l am not gonna let them get you.
我出了什么事
What's happening to me?
對不起了
I'm sorry.
你沒通過測驗  艾希先生
You didn't make it, Mr.Ash.
我希望
l wish
我能和你一起走  走出矩陣  回到現實
l could go with you.
你知道  我不怪你
I don't blame you, you know.
崔妮蒂  一切發生的事情  都是我的錯
Everything that happened, Trinity, it was all my fault.
那些"偷看窺視鏡"的事
All that Through the Looking Glass stuff.
實在禁不起誘惑  我和傳統的人一樣
Can't get my head around it. I'm oldfashioned.
考驗和選擇是有分別的
There's a difference between a test and a choice.
起碼這次的考驗讓你了解到  你本來可以成功的
For what it's worth, I think you could've handled the truth.
這只是份工作罷了
It was just a job.
再見了  崔妮蒂
Goodbye, Trinity.
再見
Goodbye.
一個結束所有案子的案子
A case to end all cases.
矩陣化
醒醒  寶貝偵測到兩個機器人  急速朝我們方向前進
Wake up. Baby's spotted two machines heading in fast.
我看到它們了
I see them.
它們是能行走的型號  你想你可以應付得來嗎
They're runners. Think you can handle them?
瞧我的
Watch me.
好  我進來了
Okay. I'm in.
那兩個比我們以前見過同型號的聰明多了
That runner's smarter than we've seen so far.
誘餌做的漂亮  謝謝
It's quite a catch. Thanks.
它會  它可能被改造嗎
Will it? Do you think it'll convert?
那得由它自己決定
To convert is its choice to make.
你認為  我們是否應該改寫它的程式
Do you think maybe we ought to reprogram it?
不行  我們不應強迫它聽從我們
No. We can't make slaves of them.
因為那樣太簡單了
Because that would be simpler.
我們不會把它當奴隸般毆打
We won't beat the machines by making them our slaves.
最好讓它自愿加入我們
Better to let them join us by choice.
讓它們相信  加入我們是對的選擇
Make them believe the right choice is the one we want them to make.
好吧  說的對  機器是工具  制造出來就是拿來用的
All right. Yes, machines are tools. They're made to be used.
那是它們的天性  如奴隸般聽從指揮
It's their nature. To be slaves.
這就是為什么  要給它看一個更好的世界
That's why we can show them a better world,
使它自愿加入我們
why they convert.
-但是我們給它們看的世界  不是真實的  -沒關系
-But that world we show them isn't real. -lt doesn't matter.
我擔心它們會發現  那只是我們想像出來的世界
I'm afraid they'll figure out that we've made up the thing in our heads.
它們看不出差別  對人工智能來說
They can't tell the difference. To an artificial mind,
所有的現實都是虛擬的
all reality is virtual.
它們如何知道那個真實世界  其實也是虛擬出來的
How do they know that the real world isn't just another simulation?
我們又如何知道
How do you?
我知道我不是在作夢  我知道夢里應該是什么樣子的
I know I'm not dreaming now because l know what it's like being in a dream.
所以夢讓你了解現實的存在
So dreaming lets you know reality exists.
不  只是我的思想存在而已  其他的  我也不知道
No. Just that my mind exists. I don't know about the rest.
好啦  修好了  看來我們也可以走了
Okay, he's good to go. Looks like we are too.
已經在作夢了
Dreaming already?
它今天很辛苦的
He's had a rough day.
可憐的寶貝
You poor baby.
不介意幫個忙吧
Would you mind?
當然不
Not at all.
哈啰  你好
Hello there.
發生什么事了
What's happening?
敵人偵哨艇
Sentinels.
快走
Let's go!
快  可惡  幫我
Come on, damn it, help me!